Not all try block code causes an error.
Hopefully, errors are rare.
We have seen how an except statement runs
code if a try block were to cause a runtime
error.
But what if we want code to run if the try
block can run without error?
What if, for example, someone enters a legitimate
value for a game piece and no errors occur?
For that situation, we want an else statement.
Continuing the figurative language example
we started earlier in this section, we successfully
tested the try code.
We raised an error if someone entered an invalid
value for the range of figuratives.
To continue building this code, I have added
an else block to this 523-else file on lines
7 and 8 and moved the print statement to confirm
the choice made to that block.
Else runs if the try is successful.
While else is not required, we have seen that
although the else block is optional, including
it can be useful.
Without it, the code in the try block would
execute if no exceptions occur, but we would
have no way to easily specify additional actions
to take specifically when the try block is
successful.
I will run this code and enter a number from
1 through 5.
The code works, and we get a matching figurative.
I will run the code again and enter a bad
value, and, as expected, we get the exception
message.
To recap what we have learned so far in this
section: a try block tries to run code without
an error.
If an error occurs, the except block runs.
If no errors occur, the else block runs.
We need an except block for an else block
to work.